IT NETWORK ASSISTANT

Profile

Over 3 years of experiance in network engineer and IT Projects. Experience in configuring, maintaining LAN and WAN networks. Skilled in trubleshoting areas Switching, routing, security and IT project management. *Troubleshooting and network performance analysis skills. *Strong knowledge in OSI layers and Telnet, SSH connection, routing and switching. Skills

- subnetting, VLSM and TCP/IP protocol suite (IP, ARP, ICMP, TCP, TFTP)
- Comprehensive understanding of WAN security (GRE Tunnels, PPPOE, and PPP)
- Good experience in VLAN, VTP, STP and Port security configuration.
- Microsoft Office Suite, MS Project 2010, Share Point.

Accomplishments

• Certifications:.

Professional Experience 02/2016 to 08/2016

IT Network Assistant Diamond Ranch Academy i1/4 Cedar City, UT

- Designed and implemented new computer LABs project, resulting in 20% student's capacity growth.
- Successfully applied VLANs and VTP protocol on the new computer LABs, leading easy network administration.
- Increased network performance 35% by implementing the right solutions and Configured RSTP on switches.
- Applied security port configuration and port-security violation successfully to better protect the network from any illegal use.
- Implemented traffic filters on Cisco routes using Standard and Extended access-list.
- Provided network administrator support for LAN/WAN, maintained and troubleshot TCP/IP, NAT, DHCP, VLANs Routers, and Switches
- Troubleshoot LAN/WAN, and network issues and coordinates/escalates issues with appropriate staff for problem resolution.
- Monitored and managed tickets queue, prioritized tasks, and Updated daily documents.

05/2012 to 08/2014

Pre-sales Engineer

- Met customer's requirements and business needs by designing and integrating small to medium LANs/WANs solutions.
- Evaluated clients' needs, provided quotes, offered Data Center (TIA-942) and Network Infrastructure solutions, and ensure customer's satisfaction.
- Provided help in installing Internet, Security, Network, Wireless Network, installation of Routers and Switchs and troubleshooting.
- Managed three projects' procurement process, all of them delivered on time and within cost.
- Assisted the Network Administrator on installation and maintenance of all network devices within the CISCO network.
- Provided help the NOC technicians in Troubleshooting LAN/WAN and network issues and coordinates/escalates issues with appropriate staff for problem resolution.

12/2010 to 08/2014 Uipath i¹/₄ Newark , NJ 01/2010 to 05/2012 Project coordinator

- Managed and controlled company's projects budget, resulting in 15% profit growth.
- Supervised and Implemented Al-Assad Hospital's \$8M Data Center Project; Delivered on time, within the scope and met TIA 942 data center standard.
- Executed risk management plan to \$1.5M Nestle manufacture's security project within time.
- Coordinated between ICT department and PMO (Project Management Office) units, resulting in meeting the budget, time frame, and project needs.
- Documented and filed all forms required for independent project management process group during project life cycles, to meet the PMP standers.

Education and Training

2009

Bachelor degree: Computer Science University of Kalamon il/4 City, State Computer Science

Certifications

Interconnection Cisco Network Device ICND1, CISCO certified 2016 CCNA Routing and Switchingcurrently enrolled Project Management Training, Venture International 2012

Skills

budget, CCNA, CISCO, CISCO certified, clients, designing, DHCP, forms, frame, IP, LANs, LAN, access, Microsoft Office Suite, Office, MS Project, Share Point, Network Administrator, network administration, Network, PPP, problem resolution, procurement, profit, Project Management, risk management, Routers, Routing, Switches, TCP/IP, Troubleshoot, Troubleshooting, WAN, WANs